Guide to the Rice University Geology Department papers, 1951-1991 UA 009
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Geology Department Papers
1951-1991
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University. Department of Geology and Geophysics
UA 009
22.25 Linear Feet (18 boxes)
These papers contain proposals, grants, contracts, experiments, surveys, publications, notes, newsclippings, photographs, and correspondence related to the Department of Geology between 1951 and 1991.
Historical Note
The Department of Geology at Rice University was designed and organized by Dr. Carey Croneis in 1953. Dr. Croneis became the first Harry C. Wiess professor of geology before being named acting president of Rice then Chancellor in 1960 and 1961 respectively. John A. S. Adams, with Dr. Croneis, helped found the Geology Department and later served as Chairman of the Geology Department for thirty-four years. The Geology Department has recieved grants from the Welch Foundation and the United States Atomic Energy Commission, and worked with influential companies such as PeMex and Shell. Rice University's Geology Department, today the Department of Earth Science, continues to promote exploration of the earth, the atmosphere, and the evolution of the environment.
Scope and Contents
These papers contain proposals, grants, contracts, experiments, surveys, publications, notes, newsclippings, photographs, and correspondence related to the Department of Geology between 1951 and 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at woodson@rice.edu for assistance in accessing these files.
Acquisition Note
This material was transferred to the Woodson Research Center in 1992 by J. A. S. Adams.
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Universities and colleges
Document Types
agendas (administrative records); contracts
Subjects (Persons)
Adams, John A. S. (John Allan Stewart), 1926-; Croneis, Carey
Subjects (Corporations)
Rice University. Department of Geology and Geophysics
- Series I: General Papers, 1952-1991; 150594
  - Geology Dept., 1982-1983; 150595 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Geology Dept., 1981; 150596 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Geology Dept., 1980; 150597 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Geology Dept., 1978-1979; 150598 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Geology Dept., 1976-1977; 150599 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Geology Dept., 1970-1975; 150600 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Geology Dept., 1963-1968; 150601 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Geology Dept., 1983-1991; 150995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Programmed Disengagment" of J.A.S. Adams, 1980-1988; 150996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports (Salary, Letters, etc.), 1963-1987; 150997 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Continental Oil Company, 1966-1970; 150998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Croneis Professorship in Geology, 1971-1975; 150999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Houston Gem and Mineral Show, 1972; 151000 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - John S. Ivy, 1952-1978; 151001 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minority Group, 1968; 151002 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - PeMex Grant, 1965-1970; 151003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - PeMex, 1965-1969; 151004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - PeMex - Publicity, 1965; 151005 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Sharp Travel Fund, 1973-1977; 151006 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Texas Gulf Sulfur, 1965-1966; 151007 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Television (Rice TV Show), 1957; 151008 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series II: Lab Equipment, Materials, and Procedures, 1951-1987; 151009
  - Analyzed Standards, 1952-1975; 151016 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scintillometer, 1965-1967; 151017 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Gamma-Ray Spectrometer, 1957; 151018 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Low-Level Radiation Lab, 1962-1967; 151019 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mica Separator (Seed Separator), 151020 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Gamma-Spectrometer (Portable), 1955-1962; 151021 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Harshaw Crystals, 1959-1974; 151022 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Lightnin" Mixer, 151023 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Scintillometer-Field-C.A.E., 1953-1959; 151024 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Wilfley Table, 1960; 151025 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Petrographic Microscopes Welch Bausch and Lomb Petrographic, 1960; 151026 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Artec Materials, 1979-1982; 151027 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Demineralizer-Barnstead, 1951; 151028 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Simpson Test Meter, 151029 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Surveying Altimeter, 151030 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Gamma-Ray Spectrometers (multi-channel), 1961-1975; 151031 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Tempco GRP Furnace, 151032 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Mass Spectrometer, 1971-1984; 151033 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Health and Safety Laboratory, 1962; 151034 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Geochron Labs, 1961-1967; 151035 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Analyzed Standards, 1973-1982; 151036 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Liquid Nuclear Emulsions, 1955-1962; 151037 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Nuclear Laboratory Experiment Manual and Equipment Images, 1970-1977; 151038 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Safety and Repair, 1974-1987; 151039 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Bauxite: Maps and Data, 1977-1980; 151040 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bauxite, 1956-1960; 151041 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Research Corporation, 1959; 151042 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Portable Gamma Ray Spectrometers, 1969-1979; 151043 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Series III: Surveys and Experiments, 1961-1984; 151044
  - Field Books I, 1964-1975; 151045 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Field Books II and Map Line Negatives, 1961-1964; 151046 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Beutronite Data, 1981-1982; 151047 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sierra Blanca Intrusives-Eagle MTS, 1984; 151048 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Northern Quitman Granites, 1984; 151049 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Square Peak Volcanics, 1984; 151050 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - SPV Groundmass, 1984; 151051 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Oklahoma Data Area, 1971; 151052 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Oklahoma Data: Area Conversion, 1971; 151053 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Oklahoma Data: Area V, 1971; 151054 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Oklahoma Data: Area II, III, and IV, 1971; 151055 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Oklahoma Data: Area I, 1971; 151056 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Oklahoma Survey Data Reduction, 151057 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Oklahoma Paper, 151058 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Oklahoma, 1970; 151059 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Puerto Rico Results and Notes, 1964-1970; 151060 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Crystal City/Beeville Study, 1979-1980; 151061 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Petrograph Data, 1965-1971; 151062 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Record of KCl Experiment at Rice, 1970; 151063 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - United States Atomic Energy Commission (USAEC) Airborne Radiometric Reconnaissance, 1966; 151064 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Geologic Implications of Aeromagnetic Data, 1971; 151065 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Aerial Radiological Measuring System, 1961; 151066 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Shell Oil Company: Manual for the Application of Aerial Gamma-Ray Spectrometer Data, 1978; 151067 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Airborne Gamma-Ray Data Sheets, 1970; 151068 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Helicopter Flights - Tape Recordings, 1969-1970; 151069 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Maps, 1970; 151070 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Survey for Houston Lighting and Power Co., 1973; 151071 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Aerial Survey Publications, 1972-1979; 151072 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Helicopter Surveys, 1966-1972; 151073 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Natural Radiation Environment Symposia II-III, 151083
  - The Natural Radiation Environment II Program and Abstract, 1972; 151085 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Natural Radiation Environment (NRE) Papers I, 1972; 151087 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Natural Radiation Environment (NRE) Papers II, 1971-1973; 151088 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Natural Radiation Environment (NRE) Papers III, 1971-1973; 151091 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Natural Radiation Environment (NRE) III Papers I, 1976-1978; 151093 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Natural Radiation Environment (NRE) III Papers II, 1980-1981; 151095 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Series V: Proposals, Grants, and Contracts, 151103
  - Research Proposal Notes, 1981-1986; 151104 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Oxygen, 1973-1975; 151105 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Uranium Source Book, 1968-1972; 151106 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) Subcontract, 1959-1965; 151107 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Salt Mine, 1954-1965; 151108 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Research Proposals, 1978; 151109 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) - Grand Junction, 1969; 151110 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) - Grand Junction, 1968; 151111 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) - Grand Junction, 1966; 151112 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) Oak Ridge National Laboratories, 1960-1964; 151113 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) - Grand Junction, 1967; 151114 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) - Grand Junction, 1970-1971; 151115 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) - Grand Junction, 1969-1972; 151116 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Welch Foundation Grant: Financial Statement, 1985-1986; 151117 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Welch Foundation Grant, 1955-1962; 151118 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Robert A. Welch Foundation Grant (Renewed), 1961-1971; 151119 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Robert A. Welch Foundation Grant, 1972-1978; 151120 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Robert A. Welch Foundation Grant, 1978-1985; 151121 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Series VI: Welch Foundation Grant Field Data Notebooks, 151122
  - Notebook XX, 1982-1983; 151123 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks P, N, 1972-1979; 151124 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks M, N, O, 1958-1960; 151125 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Notebook T, 1960; 151126 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks LL, OO, 1970-1979; 151127 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks Y, Z, 1962-1963; 151128 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks L, S, 1957-1963; 151129 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks A, B, 1955-1957; 151130 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks JJ, KK, 1970-1972; 151132 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks CC, EE, GG, 1967-1971; 151133 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks HH, II, 1967-1969; 151134 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks C, K, 1956-1958; 151135 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Notebook E, 1955-1983; 151136 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks AA, BB, 1962-1975; 151137 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks G, H, 1957-1975; 151138 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Notebooks J, I, 1957-1961; 151142 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks D, F, 1956-1958; 151143 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks QQ, TT, VV, 1979-1983; 151144 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Notebooks X, W, 1961-1963; 151145 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks U, V, 1960-1965; 151146 (Box 17, Box 3)
  - Notebooks Q, R, 1959-1963; 151147 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Notebook P, 1957-1959; 151148 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Comanche Peak Survey 2, 151376 (Box 18, Folder 1)